<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Jekyll | Aaron Miler]]></title>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/categories/jekyll/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-06T11:26:38-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://aaronmiler.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aaron Miler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now Built with Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/now-built-with-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T22:31:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronmiler.com/blog/now-built-with-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve deployed my new blog using Otopress. I had been using Jekyll for the past couple of weeks, but I found very quickly that making changes, then rebuildling/testing was very time consuming, and rather annoying. One nice thing about Octopress is that I can simply run the server like I would a rails application and it will pay attention to changes and rebuild the site as needed.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>In the process of moving to Octopress I did have to fix some things on my local development environment. I kept getting an error from RVM that the GCC compiler wasn&rsquo;t working, and it was unable to create executables. After looking around stack overflow it seemed like a simple xCode issue. So I tinkered with that for a while.</p>

<p>After about a half hour of tinkering, I realized I wasn&rsquo;t really going anywhere with this. I&rsquo;m a huge advocate for Railsinstaller. If I need to get a machine up and running with rails quickly, that is always the route I take. However it seemed that some of the defaults that Railsinstaller used when I put it on my system kind of backed my RVM into a corner, and I was unable to update. Now Railsinstaller comes with a uninstallation option, so I simply uninstalled it, and reinstalled RVM with the normal install command.</p>

<p>In almost no time RVM installed with no gotchas, and Rails 4.0 was installed successfully. It was a rather quick and painless fix, and hopefully now I&rsquo;ll have a little bit more freedom with my RVM installation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
