<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gem | Aaron Miler]]></title>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/categories/gem/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-06T11:25:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://aaronmiler.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aaron Miler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manipulating Files with the GitHub API Gem]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/manipulating-files-with-github-api-gem/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-06T15:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronmiler.com/blog/manipulating-files-with-github-api-gem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been building an application, that is for creating, managing and organizing all those little bits of code you have floating around in your brain. Every piece of knowledge you save within the application gets saved to GitHub in your own personal repository.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;m using two different Gems to interact with the GitHub API. I&rsquo;m using the <a href="https://github.com/peter-murach/github">GitHub API Gem</a> by Piotr Murach, as well as the <a href="https://github.com/octokit/octokit.rb">Octokit</a> gem which is maintained by GitHub. Most of the interaction I&rsquo;m doing with the GitHub API is with Piotr&rsquo;s gem, however the Octokit gem has new features implemented faster.</p>

<p>A pivotal piece of this application, is the ability to create, remove, and update files. So being more comfortable with Pitor&rsquo;s gem, I decided to use it for the file manipulation.</p>

<p>I was able to find some <a href="https://github.com/peter-murach/github/wiki#githubapi-committing-file">documentation in the Github</a> repo outlining how to create a file. However, as it turns out, the documentation is very dated.</p>

<p>So I took matters into my own hands and looked at the source code to figure out what&rsquo;s going on. Finally after hours of banging my head against the wall, I found the solution I was looking for.</p>

<p>My gift to you, is what you need to create/update/remove a file using Pitor Murach&rsquo;s Github_API Gem.</p>

<p>All Methods use the Github Repo Contents method to interact with the Repo Contents API
<code>ruby
github = Github::Repos::Contents.new  :user =&gt; 'username',
  :oauth_token =&gt; 'oauth_token',
  :repo =&gt; 'repo_name'
</code></p>

<h3>Creating a File</h3>

<p>```ruby
github.create &lsquo;username&rsquo;, &lsquo;repo_name&rsquo;, &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;,
  :path => &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;,
  :message => &lsquo;Your commit message&rsquo;,
  :content => &lsquo;The contents of your file&rsquo;</p>

<h1>Content is all Base64 encoded to/from the API, and when you create a file it encodes it automatically for you</h1>

<p>```</p>

<h3>Update a File</h3>

<p>```ruby</p>

<h1>First you need to find the file so you can get the SHA you&rsquo;re updating off of</h1>

<p>file = github.find :path => &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;</p>

<h1>Then update the file just like you do with creating</h1>

<p>github.update &lsquo;username&rsquo;, &lsquo;repo_name&rsquo;, &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;,
  :path => &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;
  :message => &lsquo;Your commit message&rsquo;,
  :content => self.markdown,
  :sha => file.sha
```</p>

<h3>Removing a File</h3>

<p>```ruby</p>

<h1>First you need to find the file so you can get the SHA you&rsquo;re removing</h1>

<p>file = github.find :path => &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;</p>

<p>github.delete &lsquo;username&rsquo;, &lsquo;tome-of-knowledge&rsquo;, &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;,
  :path => &lsquo;full_path_to/file.ext&rsquo;,
  :message => &lsquo;Your Commit Message&rsquo;,
  :sha => file.sha
```</p>

<p>There you have it. I plan to send in a pull-request to update the documentation. Hope this saves someone some time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Devise Invitable]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/using-devise-invitable/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-28T10:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronmiler.com/blog/using-devise-invitable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love using Devise for application authentication. When I was creating the <a href="https://github.com/quangoinc/realtime_qa">Realtime QA Tool</a> I needed to make sure that the sign up form wasn&rsquo;t publicly accessible. So I started doing a little bit of searching I found <a href="https://github.com/scambra/devise_invitable">Devise Invitable</a>. Devise invitable allows you to invite users via e-mail to your application.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Getting up and running with Devise Invitable is really easy. The documentation is pretty good and walks you through the setup process step by step.</p>

<p>You start out with two simple commands</p>

<p><code>
rails generate devise_invitable:install
rails generate devise_invitable MODEL
</code></p>

<p>Then, update your devise model to include the <code>:invitable</code> module
<code>ruby
class User &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  devise :database_authenticatable, :confirmable, :invitable
end
</code></p>

<p>and you&rsquo;re good to go.</p>

<p>After Devise Invitable is installed and ready to go, I usually end up making an invitation action in one of my controllers. Devise Invitable does allow you to make a dedicated controller for it. But I find I can usually accomplish everything with a simple action that looks something like that</p>

<p><code>ruby
def invite_user
  @user = User.invite!(:email =&gt; params[:user][:email], :name =&gt; params[:user][:name])
  render :json =&gt; @user
end
</code>
Just like that, you can now invite users to your application.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
