<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | Aaron Miler]]></title>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-21T11:11:33-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://aaronmiler.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aaron Miler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Octopress and Github to Host My Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/hosting-your-octopress-blog-on-github/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-29T20:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronmiler.com/blog/hosting-your-octopress-blog-on-github</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I started building my site on Octopress. Coming from Jekyll everything was rather familiar. While developing my site, I listened to a great podcast, called &ldquo;Jekyll and CMS-less websites with Young Hahn and Dave Cole&rdquo; on The Web Ahead. I won&rsquo;t attempt to summarize it as there is so much covered, and it really got me excited about using Jekyll. If you haven&rsquo;t listened to it, you can listen to it <a href="http://5by5.tv/webahead/54">here</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p> As I got closer to finishing my site, I started to wonder about how I was going to host it. With my initial Jekyll set up I had just uploaded the static files to a Digital Ocean VPS and called it a day. But the Jekyll podcast got me thinking about hosting my site on GitHub pages for free, so I gave it a shot.</p>

<p>Very quickly I realized how easy it was to throw my site up on github pages. The directions for all of the pieces are a little scattered, so I figured I&rsquo;d put them all here for other Internet goers to enjoy.</p>

<h3>Setting up your GitHub Repo.</h3>

<p><a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a> allows you to host static content on GitHub for free. There are two different type of GitHub Pages. There are Project Pages, and User/Orginization pages. The User/Orinization pages must follow this formation <em>username/username.github.io</em> and you can only create your own User/Org pages, you can&rsquo;t take somebody else&rsquo;s name. Project Pages behave a little differently. All you have to do for any given project is add a branch called gh-pages and that is the branch that GitHub will use to build the site. The User/Org page can be accessed from <a href="http://username.github.io">http://username.github.io</a> while the project pages are accessed from <a href="http://username.github.io/project.">http://username.github.io/project.</a></p>

<h3>Setting up your Octopress</h3>

<p>Out of the box Octopress is already all wired up to deploy to GitHub, all you have to do is give it the destination. All you have to do is:</p>

<ul>
<li>Run <em>rake setup_github_pages</em></li>
<li>Paste in your repo URL</li>
</ul>


<p>Octopress will then detect if its a User/Org repo, or a project page repo, and create the branches accordingly. If it&rsquo;s a user/org repo it will create your master branch, if it is a project page it will create the gh-pages branch for you.</p>

<h3>Deploying to GitHub</h3>

<p>As if this wasn&rsquo;t easy enough already, this part was just a breeze. All it takes, is running two simple commands</p>

<p><code>
rake generate
rake deploy
</code></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it. Octopress will push your blog to gitHub, and GitHub will build your pages. Since you&rsquo;re pushing static files to GitHub, you don&rsquo;t have to wait for it to compile the page like you would if it were pushing Jekyll source to gitHub.</p>

<h3>Adding your custom domain name</h3>

<p>GitHub makes this almost too easy. First go into your DNS settings and point your domain name to <code>204.232.175.78</code>. Then in the root of your site, add a file called CNAME. My cname file looks like this
<code>
aaronmiler.com
</code></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s that easy. GitHub will set up some automatic redirects such as redirecting www.aaronmiler.com to aaronmiler.com, and it will also redirect traffic from aaronmiler.github.io to aaronmiler.com.</p>

<p>I was blown away by how easy this was. I&rsquo;ve often at work created very small rails apps for simple sites, or resorted to using Wordpress. After using Octopress, and Jekyll to push my content to GitHub. I think I have now found my new work flow for smaller sites.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now Built with Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/now-built-with-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T22:31:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronmiler.com/blog/now-built-with-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve deployed my new blog using Otopress. I had been using Jekyll for the past couple of weeks, but I found very quickly that making changes, then rebuildling/testing was very time consuming, and rather annoying. One nice thing about Octopress is that I can simply run the server like I would a rails application and it will pay attention to changes and rebuild the site as needed.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>In the process of moving to Octopress I did have to fix some things on my local development environment. I kept getting an error from RVM that the GCC compiler wasn&rsquo;t working, and it was unable to create executables. After looking around stack overflow it seemed like a simple xCode issue. So I tinkered with that for a while.</p>

<p>After about a half hour of tinkering, I realized I wasn&rsquo;t really going anywhere with this. I&rsquo;m a huge advocate for Railsinstaller. If I need to get a machine up and running with rails quickly, that is always the route I take. However it seemed that some of the defaults that Railsinstaller used when I put it on my system kind of backed my RVM into a corner, and I was unable to update. Now Railsinstaller comes with a uninstallation option, so I simply uninstalled it, and reinstalled RVM with the normal install command.</p>

<p>In almost no time RVM installed with no gotchas, and Rails 4.0 was installed successfully. It was a rather quick and painless fix, and hopefully now I&rsquo;ll have a little bit more freedom with my RVM installation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
