<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Shortcuts | Aaron Miler]]></title>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/categories/shortcuts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-09T19:10:05-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://aaronmiler.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aaron Miler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reload Chrome from Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronmiler.com/blog/reload-chrome-from-vim/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-17T20:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronmiler.com/blog/reload-chrome-from-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As my proficiency in vim increases. I&rsquo;ve started looking for little short cuts. At the office, I have two monitors, and do some front end development from time to time. The annoying thing about it, is ever since I&rsquo;ve switched to vim, I find CMD+Tabbing out of the terminal exceedingly annoying.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Then, I happened upon <a href="https://github.com/prasmussen/chrome-cli">Chrome CLI</a> which allows you to send commands to chrome from the command line.</p>

<p>One of the commands that is particularly useful, is the <code>Reload active tab</code> command. Which is issued with <code>chrome-cli reload</code></p>

<p>Another thing that I recently learned, is that you can issue commands to the terminal from Vim as well. All you have to do is prepend your command with a bang (!) and you can issue any command, such as <code>!open .</code> to open the current directory in the finder. Which I use quite frequently.</p>

<p>With these two factoids in my brain, I was able to create a line in my Vim RC file to reload the active chrome tab with a simple keystroke.</p>

<p>Now, when you enter in a shell command into Vim, it pops you out of vim, and waits for input to proceed. So what this command does is this.</p>

<p><code>vim
" Reload the active chrome tab
:! chrome-cli reload
" Press Enter to execute
&lt;CR&gt;
" Press Enter again to pop back into Vim
&lt;CR&gt;
</code></p>

<p>Here is what it looks like when it&rsquo;s mapped to my leader shortcut</p>

<p><code>vim
map &lt;Leader&gt;r :! chrome-cli reload&lt;CR&gt;&lt;CR&gt;
</code></p>

<p>This allows me to put Vim on one monitor, and chrome on the other. So I can just save, then hit <code>&lt;Leader&gt;+r</code> to reload the tab without leaving Vim.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m tempted to add a save before the reload in order to lessen the keystrokes even more, but I haven&rsquo;t been annoyed enough quite yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
